

ERICK ALONZO ESCOLERO

IT SUPPORT SPECIALIST

PROFILE

Solutions-focused, team oriented IT SUPPORT SPECIALIST with broadbased experience and hands-on skill in the helpdesk, customer and technical support operations. With an in-depth understanding of computer hardware and software, including installation, configuration, management, troubleshooting, and support.

CONTACT

PHONE:

323-761-0704

PROFESSIONAL PROFILES:

Linked in

www.linkedin.com/in/ericescolero

EMAIL:

escolero.enterprises@gmail.com

MILITARY SERVICE

Branch: United States Marine Corps Rank: Lance Corporal

CERTIFICATIONS

A+ Certified
July 2001 to Present
MCPS: Microsoft Certified Professional
July 2001 to Present

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

Team Leader

GEO Group Correction Facility - McFarland, CA October 2014 to August 2019

- Attended Team Building seminars (Global Leadership Summit)
- Attended Community College and self-help programs.
- Led worship services and was part of the church leadership.

IT Lead / Loss Prevention Technician

Beauty Supply Warehouse - Las Vegas, NV September 2013 to September 2014

- Maintained POS systems at retail stores operable using cutting-edge technology for processing cash or credit transactions.
- Manage and handled all IT operations at a retail and corporate level without the need to hire outside IT support.
- Aided Loss Prevention department in the installations and network configurations of hardware and software peripherals saving company time and money.

IT Computer Support Specialists

TEKSystems - Ontario, CA January 2013 to May 2013

Contracted temporarily. Project ended after 5 months.

• Helped facilitate a project to change all computer systems at Loma Linda Hospital that included upgrading hardware and software, computers, monitors, printers, and other network peripherals.

IT Manager / Data Security Manager

3RNetwork - Chino, CA January 2012 to August 2012

- As the security lead manager, project managed the installation and configuration of Blancco Server Edition and Tabernus Enterprise Erase Array software and hardware levels.
- Assisted in the NAID certification and maintain Data Destruction Department at NAID requirements and specifications.
- Defined and implemented improved corporate policies regarding the location, safety and security of servers and equipment.
- Recommended modifications to improve speed of operations and system security
- Configured and managed AD, Exchange, DHCP, Antivirus and backup servers, in the corporate network.
- Managed and cross-train students from vocation school to complete 160 hours of externship program.
- Responsible for managing the company's CCTV security camera system.
- Responsible for scheduling and training employees.

EDUCATION & TRAINING

Coastline Community College / College Christian Theology (TUMI)

July 2015 to August 2019

• Business management, marketing, personal finances.

Computer Education Institute (CEI)

Vocational School

July 2001 to November 2002

- Computer Network / PC Repair
- Received A+, and MCP

Venice High School

1996 to 2000

• High School Diploma

OTHER EXPERIENCE

Multi-Level Marketing / Network Marketing May 2011 to September 2014

, '

Companies: Organo Gold, TLC, Melalueca

Skills Acquired:

• Leadership, Team-Building, Internet Marketing, Affiliate Marketing, Sales, Blogging, AdWords, YouTube Marketing, SEO, Social Media Marketing, etc...

REFERENCES

Available Upon Request

Network Administrator Assistant

Ketab Corp - Westwood, CA June 2010 to September 2011

- IT assistant for a medium size company where I help manage about 30 computers.
- Perform weekly backups to server, fresh installed new OS to all computers and configured them in our servers.
- Configured network printers. Help manage active directory, help manage and maintain company websites.

CIA/Computer Tech

Geek Squad/Best Buy - Los Angeles, CA October 2009 to September 2011

- Assist customers with any computer problems.
- Resolved customer concerns in a positive and helpful manner.
- Troubleshoot and fix laptops, desktops, and netbooks with any hardware and software problems.
- Perform Diagnostics, Data backup, software and hardware installs.
- Perform virus removals.